<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Khirod's Blog - Chess</title><link href="https://yagami26.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://yagami26.github.io/feeds/chess.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://yagami26.github.io/</id><updated>2025-02-09T21:36:00+05:30</updated><subtitle>writing about tech and randomness in universe</subtitle><entry><title>Rook Strategy</title><link href="https://yagami26.github.io/chess/post-18.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-02-09T21:36:00+05:30</published><updated>2025-02-09T21:36:00+05:30</updated><author><name>khirod</name></author><id>tag:yagami26.github.io,2025-02-09:/chess/post-18.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was a little bored of reading the endgames, and wanted to read something different for a change. I was already reading Reassess Your Chess (also by Jeremy Silman). It's a good book, but as per my chess dojo, this book is too advanced and should not be read by …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was a little bored of reading the endgames, and wanted to read something different for a change. I was already reading Reassess Your Chess (also by Jeremy Silman). It's a good book, but as per my chess dojo, this book is too advanced and should not be read by my rating range :P. But I think getting exposure to ideas is not a bad thing.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not want to read about knights and bishops, so I decided to read about rooks. Also because I do feel I rarely use rooks efficiently in the game. So having a strategy or two for rooks should not be bad. I came across two interesting techniques.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using a piece to create interference to occupy a file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doubling up rooks just below a pawn which you can exchange, Jeremy mentions it as holding the trigger to a gun. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the two games&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Interference to occupy a file&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe id="12789551" allowtransparency="true" frameborder="0" style="width:100%;border:none;height:300px" src="https://www.chess.com/emboard?id=12789551"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script nonce="chesscom-diagram"&gt;window.addEventListener("message",e=&gt;{e['data']&amp;&amp;"12789551"===e['data']['id']&amp;&amp;document.getElementById(`${e['data']['id']}`)&amp;&amp;(document.getElementById(`${e['data']['id']}`).style.height=`${e['data']['frameHeight']+37}px`)});&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Trigger to a gun&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe id="12789565" allowtransparency="true" frameborder="0" style="width:100%;border:none;height:300px" src="https://www.chess.com/emboard?id=12789565"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script nonce="chesscom-diagram"&gt;window.addEventListener("message",e=&gt;{e['data']&amp;&amp;"12789565"===e['data']['id']&amp;&amp;document.getElementById(`${e['data']['id']}`)&amp;&amp;(document.getElementById(`${e['data']['id']}`).style.height=`${e['data']['frameHeight']+37}px`)});&lt;/script&gt;</content><category term="Chess"></category><category term="chess"></category><category term="chess-strategy"></category></entry><entry><title>Various forms of opposition in chess</title><link href="https://yagami26.github.io/chess/post-17.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-02-09T11:59:00+05:30</published><updated>2025-02-09T11:59:00+05:30</updated><author><name>khirod</name></author><id>tag:yagami26.github.io,2025-02-09:/chess/post-17.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;From silman endgames that as long as two kings are on board opposition exists. It's a little easier to determine when the king and pawn were placed only one square in front of each other, and whoever had to move didn't have opposition back then. There are other forms of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;From silman endgames that as long as two kings are on board opposition exists. It's a little easier to determine when the king and pawn were placed only one square in front of each other, and whoever had to move didn't have opposition back then. There are other forms of opposition&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Diagonal Opposition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same concept applies for when both the kings are on diagonals. See the below image &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://yagami26.github.io/images/diagonal-opposition.png" alt="Sample Image" height="300", width="300"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here the white king on d4 and black king on h8 are on same black diagonal, also notice the number of squares in between the diagonal is 3, since there is odd number of squares between them whoever has to move doesn't have the opposition.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think about it it's not so different from the last post where the kings were on same file and separated by just one square and whoever had to move had lost the opposition. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same applies for black king at a8 and white king at c6, whoever moves loses the opposition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rule - Whenever kings occupy the same diagonal, and if there exists an odd number of squares between them, then the side to move doesn't have opposition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Distant Opposition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not so different from diagonal opposition but the opposition which exists when the kings occupy the same file. Again the rule is same, if the number of squares between them are odd, then whoever moves has lost the opposition.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="https://yagami26.github.io/images/distant-opposition.png" alt="Sample Image" height="300", width="300"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here whoever has to move will win the opposition as there are even number of squares between them.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Magic Square Opposition (Box Opposition)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what about if both the kings don't occupy a similar color and also appear on different ranks and files. Consider the below image  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://yagami26.github.io/images/box-opposition.png" alt="Sample Image" height="300", width="300"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here the concept of opposition applies again, whoever has to move can gain the opposition here by simplifying the position to one form of opposition we already know about, in this case the position can be reduced to diagonal opposition.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;White moves by moving to Ka2 gaining distant opposition and having odd number of squares.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black moves by moving to Kg7 and gaining distant opposition with odd number of squares in between. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice if both the king kept walking towards each other, we would again gain a simpler form of 1 square opposition we are already familiar with. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rule - Whoever has to move should construct a box which should contain both kings at diagonals and all the edges of the box should have same color, to obtain the opposition. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Examples (WIP)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course this knowledge of opposition means a little if I cannot apply them successfully in the games. I'm currently practicing the endgames on chess.com to ensure that I am able to reason the best move or worst correctly. This post will be updated by examples&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Chess"></category><category term="chess"></category><category term="endgames"></category><category term="chess-theory"></category></entry><entry><title>K-P opposition patterns in Chess</title><link href="https://yagami26.github.io/chess/post-16.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-02-03T19:38:00+05:30</published><updated>2025-02-03T19:38:00+05:30</updated><author><name>khirod</name></author><id>tag:yagami26.github.io,2025-02-03:/chess/post-16.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Opposition is a concept I always knew, but never really appreciated the beauty of it. Basically a king gains opposition, when it forces other king to move and not occupy an important square. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a look at this study for eg &lt;iframe id="12760339" allowtransparency="true" frameborder="0" style="width:100%;border:none;height:500px" src="https://www.chess.com/emboard?id=12760339"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;script nonce="chesscom-diagram"&gt;window.addEventListener("message",e=&amp;gt;{e['data']&amp;amp;&amp;amp …&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Opposition is a concept I always knew, but never really appreciated the beauty of it. Basically a king gains opposition, when it forces other king to move and not occupy an important square. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a look at this study for eg &lt;iframe id="12760339" allowtransparency="true" frameborder="0" style="width:100%;border:none;height:500px" src="https://www.chess.com/emboard?id=12760339"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;script nonce="chesscom-diagram"&gt;window.addEventListener("message",e=&amp;gt;{e['data']&amp;amp;&amp;amp;"12760339"===e['data']['id']&amp;amp;&amp;amp;document.getElementById(&lt;code&gt;${e['data']['id']}&lt;/code&gt;)&amp;amp;&amp;amp;(document.getElementById(&lt;code&gt;${e['data']['id']}&lt;/code&gt;).style.height=&lt;code&gt;${e['data']['frameHeight']+37}px&lt;/code&gt;)});&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is another study to appreciate the opposition concept. &lt;iframe id="12760389" allowtransparency="true" frameborder="0" style="width:100%;border:none;height:500px;" src="https://www.chess.com/emboard?id=12760389"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;script nonce="chesscom-diagram"&gt;window.addEventListener("message",e=&amp;gt;{e['data']&amp;amp;&amp;amp;"12760389"===e['data']['id']&amp;amp;&amp;amp;document.getElementById(&lt;code&gt;${e['data']['id']}&lt;/code&gt;)&amp;amp;&amp;amp;(document.getElementById(&lt;code&gt;${e['data']['id']}&lt;/code&gt;).style.height=&lt;code&gt;${e['data']['frameHeight']+37}px&lt;/code&gt;)});&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a general rule I think we should notice the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's bad for enemy king to step in front of our promoting pawn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's bad for our king be forced to lose opposition, because losing opposition forces us to move away. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from that as far as chess update goes, I think I really enjoyed analyzing my game in classical chess. I believe classical chess is the way for me to improve and appreciate chess better. I have this tendency to make moves instinctively. Take this study of endgames for example, I spent some time today and drilled down the concept slightly better than I had yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was also interesting to do a write up of my game analysis I played as a part of Dojo (my online chess club). I had some insights. Mostly I believe I need to calm the fuck down during games and do the hard work (calculation :P), then evaluate the position and calculate variations of other candidate moves. Visualization is an exercise I think will develop with my Polgar mate exercises. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe this study will definitely be easier for me to review later. Ciao!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Chess"></category><category term="chess"></category><category term="chess-theory"></category><category term="endgames"></category></entry><entry><title>My thoughts after training for first day on ChessDojo</title><link href="https://yagami26.github.io/chess/post-14.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-01-28T08:24:00+05:30</published><updated>2025-01-28T08:24:00+05:30</updated><author><name>khirod</name></author><id>tag:yagami26.github.io,2025-01-28:/chess/post-14.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I practiced for almost 1.5 hours last night on the suggested weekly plan for my level on dojo. I had to spend 20 mins solving problems from the book by Lazslo Polgar on Mate in 2's, then focus 30 mins on reading the endgames part 1 by Jeremy Silman …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I practiced for almost 1.5 hours last night on the suggested weekly plan for my level on dojo. I had to spend 20 mins solving problems from the book by Lazslo Polgar on Mate in 2's, then focus 30 mins on reading the endgames part 1 by Jeremy Silman.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The endgames part 1 is meant for beginners, and I could say I could quickly skim through most of the pages as I'm already pretty familiar with Two Queen, Two Rooks, Queen King and Rook King endgames. So overall I think I will just finish part 1 today just to update progress on Dojo (there we have to keep a track of progress of how many pages you read and how much time you spent)  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interesting part for me however was the M2 exercises, I found out I was frequently misannotating the square names, or writing invalid moves sometimes by a queen. When you're playing most of the time online, the online board doesn't allow you to make invalid moves. I wrote a move where queen on h2 could move to Qa8, if you know anything about chess this is an invalid move. I need to work on following things from these mistakes about visualisation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowing square names, the color of the square, and probably the squares adjacent to it. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowing if a piece can reach from one square to other. For king it would be adjacent squares, for pawn a square or two above or en-passant or takes, same for other pieces. I think the trickiest would be a knight. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always realised that visualisation is an important skill, and that I should start working on it. It's a little daunting to imagine all the 64 squares in your head. I would probably start including some time to practice vision exercises on chess.com, and also holding a position in head and seeing where I was wrong. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like the training program, it's intensive but as long as I keep finding out what I need to work on I dont mind paying 10 dollars a month.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Chess"></category><category term="chess"></category><category term="chessdojo"></category></entry><entry><title>I joined ChessDojo</title><link href="https://yagami26.github.io/chess/post-12.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-01-25T12:12:00+05:30</published><updated>2025-01-25T12:12:00+05:30</updated><author><name>khirod</name></author><id>tag:yagami26.github.io,2025-01-25:/chess/post-12.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I subscribed to ChessDojo membership for a month and I want to try out if a structured training program actually helps me improve more quickly, the method so far seems very sound. A community to discuss and other improvers who are part of a cohort. Let's see if I am …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I subscribed to ChessDojo membership for a month and I want to try out if a structured training program actually helps me improve more quickly, the method so far seems very sound. A community to discuss and other improvers who are part of a cohort. Let's see if I am actually able to improve. Currently I'm rating around mid 1300 on chess.com rapid&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Chess"></category><category term="chessdojo"></category><category term="chess"></category></entry></feed>