<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Khirod Blog - Chess</title><link href="https://yagami26.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://yagami26.github.io/feeds/chess.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://yagami26.github.io/</id><updated>2024-05-28T20:14:00+05:30</updated><subtitle>writing about tech and randomness in universe</subtitle><entry><title>Test chess games embed</title><link href="https://yagami26.github.io/post-7.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-05-28T20:14:00+05:30</published><updated>2024-05-28T20:14:00+05:30</updated><author><name>khirod</name></author><id>tag:yagami26.github.io,2024-05-28:/post-7.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been struggling with loneliness for several years now. I do miss having a partner in life, but I don't want to get married either. Probably because I feel if I get married in this emotional state, it will just be a patch-work/a band-aid and I'll never be …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been struggling with loneliness for several years now. I do miss having a partner in life, but I don't want to get married either. Probably because I feel if I get married in this emotional state, it will just be a patch-work/a band-aid and I'll never be able to fix the root of my emotional problem. I have always been a little distant to people, a little awkward. But I was really happy at some point in life being single, and not missing a companionship.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do feel I have moved on from her, but I never moved on the feeling of being defeated by love. That someone I cared about so much from the bottom of my heart will never love me the same way I loved them. It has always been hard to accept it. And this feeling of needing someone to feel happy about myself has stayed since then. Yes, it's a little immature of me considering I'm already 30 years old. I really want to be the guy who is happy by themselves and once I have reached that emotional state it will be the right time for me to marry.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The steps I took to avoid feeling lonely are sort of like a patch-work too. While I can't write about that here, people close to me already know about it. And that trauma doesn't help either. I feel I'm slowly getting distant to my college friends too, because I don't find anything common to discuss with them anymore. It doesn't help when they remind of the fact that I'm growing distant. It's so hard to even cry, it's like a part of me has gone numb after her. I feel choked with emotions but do not find an outlet to resolve those pent up emotions.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing about it here, helps a little, as I express a little bit of anger here. And I always said, this blog is not for regular audience, it's only for my own personal consumption. I need to get started to work, the last thing I want is to have my work impacted too because of this. This morning is not so good, but it's still a day and I should get started.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Coffee helped a bit&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe id="11853635" allowtransparency="true" frameborder="0" style="width:100%;border:none;" src="//www.chess.com/emboard?id=11853635"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script&gt;window.addEventListener("message",e=&gt;{e['data']&amp;&amp;"11853635"===e['data']['id']&amp;&amp;document.getElementById(`${e['data']['id']}`)&amp;&amp;(document.getElementById(`${e['data']['id']}`).style.height=`${e['data']['frameHeight']+30}px`)});&lt;/script&gt;</content><category term="Chess"></category><category term="chess-games"></category><category term="journal"></category></entry></feed>