<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Khirod's Blog - Linux</title><link href="https://yagami26.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://yagami26.github.io/feeds/linux.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://yagami26.github.io/</id><updated>2025-02-01T16:13:00+05:30</updated><subtitle>writing about tech and randomness in universe</subtitle><entry><title>Improving my Hyprland WM setup</title><link href="https://yagami26.github.io/post-15.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-02-01T16:13:00+05:30</published><updated>2025-02-01T16:13:00+05:30</updated><author><name>khirod</name></author><id>tag:yagami26.github.io,2025-02-01:/post-15.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In my quest for building a perfect minimalist linux system, I decided to not use a waybar. I believe it wastes a lot of screen space and doesn't really give a minimalist vibe. While waybar does look pretty sexy, I think it also wastes a lot of space. Here is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In my quest for building a perfect minimalist linux system, I decided to not use a waybar. I believe it wastes a lot of screen space and doesn't really give a minimalist vibe. While waybar does look pretty sexy, I think it also wastes a lot of space. Here is how my waybar looked like &lt;img alt="Image" src="https://yagami26.github.io/images/waybar-snapshot.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll notice it has everything, a battery monitor (fish icon), cpu usage or memory usage stats, current time/date etc. It has a workspace switcher too, it was useful for me to know which is the current (1..9) workspace. It all looked cool, but I think these docks are inspired by mac, and I didn't like the idea of wasting screen space. Think about it when you're actually working on something, how often do you look on time or the topmost panels, I reckon rarely.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I decided to ditch waybar completely from the configuration and instead use &lt;a href="https://github.com/hyprwm/hyprland-plugins/tree/main/hyprexpo"&gt;hyprexpo&lt;/a&gt; which is a hyprland plugin. I built the latest version of hyprland from git using yay and installed this hyprexpo plugin. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing I missed was having a notification system. But &lt;code&gt;dunst&lt;/code&gt; is a good way to achieve notifications too. Here is a sample notification and the entire configuration can be seen in my dotfiles. &lt;img alt="Image" src="https://yagami26.github.io/images/dunst-sample-notification.png"&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first application during startup is &lt;code&gt;wtfutil&lt;/code&gt; which will create a small dashboard on workspace 1, so I can read hackernews there, or check memory and cpu usage and also do stuff like keeping todo notes. It's very extensible and has its own configuration file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall I'm quite satisfied with how my system looks now. &lt;img alt="Image" src="https://yagami26.github.io/images/hyprland-no-waybar.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Linux"></category><category term="linux"></category><category term="arch"></category><category term="hyprland"></category></entry></feed>