<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Khirod's Blog - Music</title><link href="https://yagami26.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://yagami26.github.io/feeds/music.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://yagami26.github.io/</id><updated>2025-01-27T08:05:00+05:30</updated><subtitle>writing about tech and randomness in universe</subtitle><entry><title>Difficulty learning 6/8 soundtrack on guitar</title><link href="https://yagami26.github.io/post-13.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-01-27T08:05:00+05:30</published><updated>2025-01-27T08:05:00+05:30</updated><author><name>khirod</name></author><id>tag:yagami26.github.io,2025-01-27:/post-13.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was taught guitar in an unconventional way. It's been a decade and now I look back and see the shortcomings of the way I was taught. I was never taught rhythm or music theory, instead the focus was to play songs by feeling it and only focus on the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was taught guitar in an unconventional way. It's been a decade and now I look back and see the shortcomings of the way I was taught. I was never taught rhythm or music theory, instead the focus was to play songs by feeling it and only focus on the songs I enjoyed playing. Although it was enough to get started, I still struggle to read music theory or apply it in songs I play. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One example of it is learning 'Until I found you - Stephen Sanchez', the song uses a 6 bars in a beat style. I can of course play it without focussing on the rhythm and it doesn't sound bad either. But I will start focussing on learning rhythm the right way. Currently I'm struggling to maintain the count in my head, which is a little annoying. But hey, it's never easy to learn something new. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will post the song cover on Youtube once I have learnt it properly. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Music"></category><category term="music"></category><category term="guitar"></category></entry></feed>