<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Khirod's Blog - Music</title><link href="https://yagami26.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://yagami26.github.io/feeds/music.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://yagami26.github.io/</id><updated>2025-02-10T08:00:00+05:30</updated><subtitle>writing about tech and randomness in universe</subtitle><entry><title>Bringing back the audiophile with Marshall</title><link href="https://yagami26.github.io/post-19.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-02-10T08:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2025-02-10T08:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>khirod</name></author><id>tag:yagami26.github.io,2025-02-10:/post-19.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently bought two Marshall products, one is a Major IV headphone, the other one is their portable bluetooth speaker Embertron II   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had experience with Marshall products like their amplifiers which I use with my electric guitar. They're actually a pretty big name when it comes to their guitar …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently bought two Marshall products, one is a Major IV headphone, the other one is their portable bluetooth speaker Embertron II   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had experience with Marshall products like their amplifiers which I use with my electric guitar. They're actually a pretty big name when it comes to their guitar amps. I knew there headphones had arrived in the market around 2018 when I saw someone wearing it in street and I really liked the premium and simple design they had. I was unsure of the audio quality though. I had owned Bose QC 25 headphones before and they were pretty expensive so I knew what to expect out of a music quality of a headphone. I loved Bose for their music quality and ANC technology.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time I decided to give Marshall a try. I loved the Major IV headphones, they don't have any fancy features like ANC but they sound well, the mids are balanced, the lows not too bad and highs are sweet and sharp. The one thing I hated about my Bose was how easily the earpads can rip off and Marshall offered me the peace of mind to switch them anytime.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Embertron II is a nice equipment too. I use it to watch movies on iPad and in fact I like to sleep with some Piano music on, and last night I kept it on for entire night. It comes with a small form factor but packs a punch. I love it's lows.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I am quite satisfied with both the products. The physical knob to control audio levels, and skip tracks is just so simple and efficient design.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a small video of my &lt;a href="https://youtube.com/embed/AmHWQhUvRO4?feature=share"&gt;Embertron II&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Music"></category><category term="music"></category></entry><entry><title>Difficulty learning 6/8 soundtrack on guitar</title><link href="https://yagami26.github.io/post-13.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-01-27T08:05:00+05:30</published><updated>2025-01-27T08:05:00+05:30</updated><author><name>khirod</name></author><id>tag:yagami26.github.io,2025-01-27:/post-13.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was taught guitar in an unconventional way. It's been a decade and now I look back and see the shortcomings of the way I was taught. I was never taught rhythm or music theory, instead the focus was to play songs by feeling it and only focus on the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was taught guitar in an unconventional way. It's been a decade and now I look back and see the shortcomings of the way I was taught. I was never taught rhythm or music theory, instead the focus was to play songs by feeling it and only focus on the songs I enjoyed playing. Although it was enough to get started, I still struggle to read music theory or apply it in songs I play. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One example of it is learning 'Until I found you - Stephen Sanchez', the song uses a 6 beats in a bar style. I can of course play it without focussing on the rhythm and it doesn't sound bad either. But I will start focussing on learning rhythm the right way. Currently I'm struggling to maintain the count in my head, which is a little annoying. But hey, it's never easy to learn something new. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will post the song cover on Youtube once I have learnt it properly. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Music"></category><category term="music"></category><category term="guitar"></category></entry></feed>