<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Khirod Blog - Music</title><link href="https://yagami26.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://yagami26.github.io/feeds/music.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://yagami26.github.io/</id><updated>2024-08-10T11:22:00+05:30</updated><subtitle>writing about tech and randomness in universe</subtitle><entry><title>A new beginning</title><link href="https://yagami26.github.io/post-12.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-10T11:22:00+05:30</published><updated>2024-08-10T11:22:00+05:30</updated><author><name>khirod</name></author><id>tag:yagami26.github.io,2024-08-10:/post-12.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I could not write for a while, things were seriously fucked up, and I was very distracted. I couldn't focus on either the problem solving, nor at work, nor at any of my personal goals. The toxic relationships, the unresolved anger, everything needs an outlet, I think.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tatiana caused a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I could not write for a while, things were seriously fucked up, and I was very distracted. I couldn't focus on either the problem solving, nor at work, nor at any of my personal goals. The toxic relationships, the unresolved anger, everything needs an outlet, I think.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tatiana caused a lot of it, Karin brought me peace and calm. In the end, I only realised I could not rely on either on them to solve my problems. I need to go back to my old self. I remember a time, when music was a need. It brought calm, an escapade from problems. Practicing guitar was fun. I still like playing guitar but these days I think my primary motivation is being a show off on social media. After all, we humans are attention seekers &lt;em&gt;chuckles&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought a new Fender CD-60 SCE last week, and it sounds really beautiful. I don't plan to upload anything on instagram for a while, I'll post it on my Youtube channel instead as none of the people I know follow me on Youtube. The page is created under an alias anyway.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started learning the fingerstyle technique. I learnt songs like Gul by Anuv Jain, which actually use travis picking technique and it was a little tough too, but I feel that my right hand is getting the general hang of it. Right now I'm learning House of the Rising Sun (by Animals). It is a great introductory song to learn fingerstyle. I'll make a post and section on the blog for adding guitar songs. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Music"></category><category term="guitar"></category><category term="music"></category></entry></feed>